{
    "id": "e769e252eba94b529d72a43fa65c58b7",
    "title": "Continuous Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I …………………….. an interesting novel now.",
            "description": "We use the present continuous here because the time expression now gives the indication that we are talking about the present.",
            "answers": [
                "was reading",
                "am reading",
                "will be reading"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8152f42d38504f46aa11557b0c70e9b4"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………. with her parents at the moment.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was staying",
                "is staying",
                "will be staying"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "69e00f61fc6c4cdca5266d7f7342190b"
        },
        {
            "question": "This time tomorrow we ………………………. Raj’s birthday.",
            "description": "We use the future continuous here because we are talking about an action or situation that will be in progress at a particular point of time in future.",
            "answers": [
                "were celebrating",
                "are celebrating",
                "will be celebrating"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4a633e1d63fd457fb00ad6030e9e44b7"
        },
        {
            "question": "The child ………………………… for his parents.",
            "description": "There is no time reference here hence the present continuous is used.",
            "answers": [
                "was waiting",
                "is waiting",
                "will be waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "01ae9289ebf64577af5810fdd4d5db5f"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………… ready when she came.",
            "description": "The past tense in the subordinate clause clearly indicates that we are talking about past time.",
            "answers": [
                "was getting",
                "am getting",
                "will be getting"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1376191f07c6484bb053108f952300b2"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………… in the afternoon.",
            "description": "The present continuous can be used to talk about future events if the arrangement already exists. The future continuous is also possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "was leaving",
                "is leaving",
                "will be leaving"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "348a6b6f9fb340c388a0a75e077bfe5f"
        },
        {
            "question": "The child …………………….. soundly.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was sleeping",
                "is sleeping",
                "will be sleeping"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c4c48e8e6b9e4bed8723c87a86b2c7e2"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………… when the lights went out.",
            "description": "The past tense in the subordinate clause clearly indicates that we are talking about past time.",
            "answers": [
                "was reading",
                "am reading",
                "will be reading"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0732ca638b6c45fcbdffeb5bf81ccb93"
        },
        {
            "question": "The boys ………………………. in the park when it started raining.",
            "description": "The past tense in the subordinate clause clearly indicates that we are talking about past time.",
            "answers": [
                "were playing",
                "was playing",
                "are playing"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "13d877675ec04234935c4e42bcd649c5"
        },
        {
            "question": "We …………………… to Mexico next summer.",
            "description": "The present continuous can be used to talk about future events if the arrangement already exists. The future continuous is also possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "were going",
                "are going",
                "will be going"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "45e166657b274c389f6888d212b24192"
        },
        {
            "question": "The car …………………… for a service next week.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is going in",
                "was going in",
                "has going in"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d786cc29ebec4ef3ab66a08730c6bb1a"
        },
        {
            "question": "Don’t phone them now – they ……………………. dinner.",
            "description": "The future continuous is often used to predict the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "were having",
                "are having",
                "will be having"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "da8008a05b2a4a7ba7c6bbf55391091b"
        }
    ]
}